Petr Gavrilov

Moscow, Russia | +7 (985) 795-5422 | petter426@gmail.com | github.com/petrgavrilov | linkedin.com/in/petr-gavrilov

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Experienced front-end developer with 8 years of experience. Proficient in React and Angular building and optimizing web applications. Led tech teams to build a strong engineering culture and teamwork. As a front-end lead at the largest EdTech company, created a full-stack team for marketing development that resulted in a 30x reduction in time to market for new landings by automating product marketing. Non-EU citizen, relocation required.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Lead Frontend Developer, Skyeng

Apr 2021 - Feb 2024

Online education platform specializing in language learning, with 100,000 students and 11,000 teachers.

- Led a marketing product development team of 8 front-end, back-end, and QA engineers maintaining 20 services used by 5 marketing teams with a public website audience of over 1 million users per month.
- Designed solutions to optimize marketing launches, reducing the average time from 3 weeks to 2 hours.
- Implemented backlog grooming, design and code review resulting in >90% team efficiency for 2 years.
- Introduced automated testing practices, automating top 20 scenarios with integration and e2e testing, resulting in a 30% reduction in defect rates.
- Developed internal tool using React and Golang for scraping landing pages, allowing product managers to analyze over 4000 pages in less than 1 minute.
- Hired and mentored 4 junior front-end developers to mid-level and above.

Senior Frontend Developer, Skysmart

May 2019 - Apr 2021

Learning platform focused on children's education and exam preparation, with 120,000 lessons per month.

- Created features for the online learning platform with 10,000 daily users, including group lesson platform, interactive learning exercises, teacher's personal cabinet, and lesson builder.
- Established effective teamwork strategies between designers and developers, resulting in a 25% reduction in project completion time and improved productivity.
- Conducted over 30 technical interviews for front-end positions across 10 development teams.
- Technologies: Angular, TypeScript, RxJS, HTML, SCSS.

Middle Frontend Developer, iSimpleLab

Jul 2017 - Jan 2019

100+ employee fintech company developing SAAS for internet banking used by 40+ banks.

- Engineered critical modules for online banking SAAS: enrollment, personal finance management, utility payments.
- Led the launch of a hybrid-style mobile application, reducing the company's mobile development costs by 50%.
- Improved developer efficiency by 25% by implementing a monorepo architecture for code reuse.
- Technologies: Angular, Typescript, RxJS, Ionic, Angular Material, HTML, SCSS.

Junior Frontend Developer, Imagespark

Sep 2015 – Jan 2017

Web design agency creating websites for international and local brands.

- Delivered frontend solutions for clients such as Volkswagen, Ekanuba, and Mary Kay.
- Initiated a frontend style guide, unified development methodologies, and optimized the onboarding process.
- Technologies: HTML, CSS, LESS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Laravel.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, HTML, CSS **Technologies**: Angular, React, Node.js, SCSS, Testing Library **Languages**: English (working proficiency), Russian (native)

EDUCATION

Moscow State Technological University "Stankin", Feb 2013